Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Erika.
我是Erika。
Today we're bringing you another one of our sports lessons and this time we're going to
今天我们带来另一节体育课，这次我们要
go to a boxing match.
去看一场拳击比赛。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to be learning a language that you can use if you're talking about boxing,
所以我们将学习一些可以用来谈论拳击的语言，
but not only boxing, right?
但不仅仅是拳击，对吧？
Right.
对。
We can also use this language for describing a fight or somebody that's fighting.
我们也可以用这些语言来描述一场打斗或正在打架的人。
Okay, so not that we're asking our listeners to get into fights, but if ever you see a
好的，我们不是让听众去打架，但如果你看到
fight, at least now you'll have the language to talk about it.
一场打斗，至少现在你有语言可以谈论它了。
Exactly.
没错。
So let's listen to a dialogue for the first time.
那么让我们第一次听一下对话。
It might sound familiar.
它可能听起来很熟悉。
We have the legendary Rocky Balboa at EnglishPod fighting for the heavyweight championship.
我们有传奇的洛奇·巴尔博亚在EnglishPod为重量级冠军而战。
So let's see what happens.
让我们看看会发生什么。
Welcome back, boxing fans.
欢迎回来，拳击迷们。
My name is Rick Fields and here with me is the man with the iron jaw, Bob Copeland.
我是Rick Fields，和我一起的是铁下巴先生Bob Copeland。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢你，Rick。
We're coming to you live from Las Vegas.
我们在拉斯维加斯为您现场直播。
We're in the beautiful MGM Grand Hotel and Casino where the World Heavyweight Championship
我们在美丽的米高梅大酒店和赌场，世界重量级冠军赛
is about to get underway.
即将开始。
That's right, Bob.
没错，Bob。
We're about to witness the legendary Italian stallion himself, Rocky Balboa, square off
我们即将见证传奇的意大利种马本人，洛奇·巴尔博亚，与
against his lifetime rival, Apollo Creed.
他的终身对手阿波罗·克里德对决。
This will be a gruesome match for sure.
这肯定是一场残酷的比赛。
Both fighters are in the ring and we are about to begin.
两位拳手都在擂台上，我们即将开始。
In the blue corner, weighing in at 220 pounds, the former heavyweight champion of the world,
在蓝色角落，体重220磅，前世界重量级冠军，
the master of disaster, the one and only Apollo Creed.
灾难大师，独一无二的阿波罗·克里德。
In the red corner, weighing 218 pounds and with a record of 47 wins and 37 knockouts,
在红色角落，体重218磅，战绩47胜37次击倒，
the undefeated, undisputed heavyweight champion of the world, the Italian stallion, Rocky
不败的、无可争议的世界重量级冠军，意大利种马，洛奇·
Balboa.
巴尔博亚。
There's the bell and this fight is underway.
铃声响了，比赛开始了。
Apollo quickly attacks Rocky with quick, strong jabs.
阿波罗迅速用快速有力的刺拳攻击洛奇。
He dodges successfully and counterattacks with a strong right hook.
他成功躲闪，并用一记有力的右勾拳反击。
Apollo is cut.
阿波罗被割伤了。
Rocky landed a strong blow to his right eyebrow and cut him.
洛奇一记重拳击中他的右眉，割伤了他。
This is his chance.
这是他的机会。
Rocky quickly throws a left, right, another left.
洛奇迅速打出左拳、右拳、又一记左拳。
Apollo is getting pounded.
阿波罗正在被猛击。
Apollo recovers with a powerful haymaker and catches Rocky off guard.
阿波罗用一记强力的大摆拳恢复过来，打了洛奇一个措手不及。
He's down.
他倒下了。
The ref starts the count.
裁判开始计数。
One, two, three, four, five.
一、二、三、四、五。
Wow sounds like a great fight.
哇，听起来像一场精彩的比赛。
Amazing fight and I don't know who's going to win.
精彩的比赛，我不知道谁会赢。
Rocky apparently got knocked down.
洛奇显然被击倒了。
What do you think will happen?
你觉得会发生什么？
Well, if I know anything about Rocky Balboa, he will not stay knocked down for long.
嗯，如果我对洛奇·巴尔博亚有所了解，他不会长时间倒地不起。
All right.
好的。
Let's take a look at some of the language we saw in this dialogue in Language Takeaway.
让我们看看在“语言要点”中这个对话里的一些语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, Rickfield said that we have a very gruesome match tonight.
嗯，Rickfield说今晚我们有一场非常残酷的比赛。
A gruesome match.
一场残酷的比赛。
Gruesome.
残酷的。
All right.
好的。
So, if something is gruesome.
所以，如果某件事是残酷的。
It's really, it's bad, it's terrible, it's bloody.
它真的很糟糕、可怕、血腥。
Okay.
好的。
Bloody, terrible, very hard or like a gruesome fight would be a very bloody fight.
血腥、可怕、非常激烈，或者像一场残酷的战斗会是非常血腥的战斗。
Yeah, or a gruesome film.
是的，或者一部残酷的电影。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So, gruesome.
所以，残酷的。
Now, they mentioned that both fighters are in the ring.
现在，他们提到两位拳手都在擂台上。
Both fighters are in the ring.
两位拳手都在擂台上。
The ring.
擂台。
Okay.
好的。
So, the ring is the physical space where they fight.
所以，擂台是他们打斗的物理空间。
But isn't it square?
但它不是方形的吗？
Yeah, it is square.
是的，它是方形的。
It is not really circular, but it's called a boxing ring.
它实际上不是圆形的，但被称为拳击台。
I'm not really sure why.
我不太确定为什么。
Well, maybe one of our listeners knows and can tell us about that because I am not an
嗯，也许我们的一位听众知道并能告诉我们，因为我不是
expert on boxing.
拳击专家。
But what I do know is our next word.
但我确实知道的是我们的下一个词。
They were describing Rocky Balboa's career and they said he had 37 knockouts.
他们在描述洛奇·巴尔博亚的职业生涯，说他有过37次击倒。
Okay.
好的。
A knockout.
一次击倒。
In this sense, knockout is a noun.
在这个意义上，击倒是名词。
A knockout is when the fighter hits the other fighter and he falls to the ground and he
击倒是拳手击中另一拳手，他倒在地上，在10秒内
can't get up in 10 seconds because he's tired, he's dizzy, he's hurt.
无法站起来，因为他累了、头晕、受伤了。
Okay.
好的。
So, that's a knockout.
所以，那就是击倒。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's a technical boxing word.
所以，这是一个技术性的拳击词汇。
It's the action of falling to the ground and not getting up.
这是倒在地上不起来的行为。
Right.
对。
But there's also a verb, to knock out.
但还有一个动词，击倒。
Or to knock someone out.
或者把某人击倒。
Exactly.
没错。
So, when you say, I knocked this guy out.
所以，当你说，我把这家伙击倒了。
It means I hit him so hard that he fell to the floor and maybe he was unconscious for
意思是我打他打得太狠，他倒在地上，可能昏迷了
a while.
一会儿。
So, he fell asleep basically.
所以他基本上睡着了。
Almost.
差不多。
Yeah.
是的。
So, it's very similar.
所以，非常相似。
The noun form to the verb form.
名词形式到动词形式。
So, basically, if you knock someone out, you get a knockout.
所以，基本上，如果你把某人击倒，你就得到一次击倒。
Okay.
好的。
So, to knock someone out, a knockout.
所以，把某人击倒，一次击倒。
Alright.
好的。
Now, for our next word, we saw as Apollo quickly began to jab Rocky Balboa.
现在，对于下一个词，我们看到阿波罗迅速开始用刺拳攻击洛奇·巴尔博亚。
So, the noun, a jab.
所以，名词，刺拳。
So, a jab.
所以，刺拳。
Quick jabs.
快速的刺拳。
So, a jab is a kind of punch, right?
所以，刺拳是一种拳法，对吧？
It's a fast, short, but not very strong punch.
它是一种快速、短促但不太有力的拳。
Okay.
好的。
So, a technical boxing word, a jab.
所以，一个技术性的拳击词汇，刺拳。
A jab.
刺拳。
So, it can also be a verb, right?
所以，它也可以是动词，对吧？
Right.
对。
So, to jab.
所以，刺拳。
To jab.
刺拳。
Now, Apollo was throwing jabs and Rocky began to dodge.
现在，阿波罗在打刺拳，洛奇开始躲闪。
Alright.
好的。
And that's our next word, to dodge.
那是我们的下一个词，躲闪。
Dodge.
躲闪。
D-O-D-G-E.
D-O-D-G-E。
To dodge.
躲闪。
Alright.
好的。
So, if you dodge, you're trying to avoid getting hit.
所以，如果你躲闪，你是在试图避免被击中。
Right.
对。
So, you move your body so that you're not hit.
所以你移动身体以免被击中。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, we can also use it in different ways.
现在，我们也可以以不同的方式使用它。
Not only do you dodge when somebody's trying to punch you.
不仅仅是在有人试图打你时躲闪。
You can also, for example, dodge a bullet.
你也可以，例如，躲过一劫。
Right.
对。
So, when you dodge a bullet, you avoid some bad situation or some bad event.
所以，当你躲过一劫，你避免了一些糟糕的情况或事件。
Right.
对。
So, we have many examples of dodge used in other contexts.
所以，我们有很多躲闪在其他语境中使用的例子。
So, why don't we listen to some examples?
那么，我们为什么不听一些例子呢？
Example one.
例子一。
See that guy dodging through the traffic?
看到那个在车流中躲闪的家伙了吗？
He's going to get hit by a car if he's not careful.
如果他不小心，会被车撞到。
Example two.
例子二。
Well, the storm turned south.
嗯，风暴转向南了。
So, it looks like we managed to dodge a bullet.
所以，看起来我们设法躲过了一劫。
Example three.
例子三。
Look, you're the one who is in charge of sales and the numbers are down.
听着，你是负责销售的人，数字在下降。
It's your problem, so stop trying to dodge your responsibilities.
这是你的问题，所以别再试图逃避你的责任了。
You know, that word reminds me of another sport, dodgeball.
你知道吗，那个词让我想起另一项运动，躲避球。
Oh, dodgeball.
哦，躲避球。
Exactly.
没错。
Same principle.
同样的原理。
Yeah, but that's an entirely different lesson.
是的，但那完全是另一节课。
I think we need to focus here on the boxing vocabulary.
我想我们需要专注于这里的拳击词汇。
So, the announcers said that Apollo is getting pounded.
所以，解说员说阿波罗正在被猛击。
To get pounded.
被猛击。
Now, if someone is getting pounded.
现在，如果有人被猛击。
They're getting hit really hard.
他们被打得很狠。
And a lot.
而且很多。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
So, to get pounded.
所以，被猛击。
Get pounded.
被猛击。
And now, we have one more word and it's also another boxing term called a haymaker.
现在，我们还有一个词，也是另一个拳击术语，叫大摆拳。
A powerful haymaker.
一记有力的大摆拳。
Okay.
好的。
So, Apollo received a powerful haymaker.
所以，阿波罗挨了一记有力的大摆拳。
Now, this word is actually new to me.
现在，这个词对我来说其实是新的。
So, Marco, what does it mean?
所以，Marco，它是什么意思？
Basically, it's a very strong, very wild punch.
基本上，它是一种非常有力、非常狂野的拳。
Okay.
好的。
So, you don't have really good form.
所以，你的姿势不太好。
Your body is kind of moving all over the place.
你的身体到处移动。
Right.
对。
So, you don't have much balance.
所以，你不太平衡。
So, you just throw your entire body and your fist at someone to hit them as hard as you
所以你只是把整个身体和拳头扔向某人，尽可能用力地
can.
打他们。
That's a haymaker.
那就是大摆拳。
All right.
好的。
A technical boxing word here for you guys.
这里给你们一个技术性的拳击词汇。
But now, we've got some interesting phrases for you on Fluency Builder.
但现在，我们在“流利度提升”中为你们准备了一些有趣的短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
All right.
好的。
So, on Fluency Builder today, we're going to take a look at some of these phrases and
所以，在今天的“流利度提升”中，我们将看看这些短语中的一些，
we have four of them for you today.
今天有四个给你们。
So, let's get started with the first one.
让我们从第一个开始。
Well, the announcer said that the boxing match was about to get underway.
嗯，解说员说拳击比赛即将开始。
Okay.
好的。
To get underway.
开始。
So, again, this is another way of saying about to begin.
所以，这又是“即将开始”的另一种说法。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So, we're about to get underway with this new project.
所以，我们即将开始这个新项目。
Or the meeting's just about to get underway.
或者会议即将开始。
So, make sure everyone's here.
所以，确保每个人都在这里。
Very good.
非常好。
So, the match was about to get underway and the sports announcer said that Rocky Balboa
所以，比赛即将开始，体育解说员说洛奇·巴尔博亚
is going to square off against his lifetime rival.
将和他的终身对手对决。
So, we're going to look at this phrase, to square off against someone.
所以，我们将看看这个短语，与某人对决。
All right.
好的。
I'm going to square off against Jim.
我要和Jim对决。
All right.
好的。
When you square off against Jim, you get ready to fight with him or to compete with him,
当你与吉姆对峙时，你准备好与他打架或竞争。
right?
对吧？
Right.
对。
So, we're about to have a one-to-one competition.
所以，我们即将进行一对一的比赛。
So, this is like a sports word, but it's also really commonly used in a lot of different
所以，这像是一个体育词汇，但它也经常用在很多不同的
contexts.
语境中。
So, why don't we hear a few more examples of how we can use this phrase to square off.
那么，我们不妨多听几个例子，看看如何使用这个短语“to square off”。
Example one.
例子一。
The two countries are moving their armies close to the borders as they prepare to square
这两个国家正将军队调往边境附近，准备在边境争端中
off in a border dispute.
对峙。
Example two.
例子二。
Italy and Brazil are squaring off in the final game this afternoon.
意大利和巴西将在今天下午的决赛中对决。
Example three.
例子三。
Lisa and Daniel squared off against each other in the marketing meeting today.
丽莎和丹尼尔今天在营销会议上互相较量。
They were both pretty angry.
他们俩都很生气。
All right.
好的。
So, great examples, and I think we can use it now not only in boxing, but in other situations.
所以，很好的例子，我想我们现在不仅可以在拳击中使用它，还可以在其他场合使用。
Now, Bob said that Rocky landed a strong blow.
现在，鲍勃说洛奇打出了一记重拳。
To land a strong blow.
打出一记重拳。
All right.
好的。
So, land a strong blow.
所以，打出一记重拳。
Now, let's break this down.
现在，我们来分解一下。
So, a blow.
所以，一记打击。
A blow is a punch or a hit.
一记打击就是一拳或一击。
Okay.
好的。
And when you land a strong blow, what happens?
当你打出一记重拳时，会发生什么？
You basically successfully hit your opponent with a punch or hit.
你基本上成功地用一拳或一击击中了你的对手。
So, you hit them, so your fist meets their body.
所以，你打中了他们，你的拳头碰到了他们的身体。
Yes.
是的。
So, your fist landed on their body.
所以，你的拳头落在了他们的身体上。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
So, I could also change this a little bit.
所以，我也可以稍微改变一下这个说法。
I could say, I landed a punch.
我可以说，我打出了一拳。
Right.
对。
Or in boxing terms, he landed a strong left jab.
或者用拳击术语来说，他打出了一记有力的左刺拳。
Okay.
好的。
So, to land a blow.
所以，打出一记重拳。
The announcer described it as Rock threw a left.
解说员描述说洛奇打出了一记左拳。
To throw a left.
打出一记左拳。
So, he said he threw a left and a right.
所以，他说他打出了一记左拳和一记右拳。
Now again, we'll take this one apart.
现在，我们再来分解一下这个。
So, a left.
所以，一记左拳。
What are we talking about?
我们在说什么？
Basically, a left punch, but we can omit punch.
基本上，就是左拳，但我们可以省略“拳”字。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's a punch with your left hand, but the verb throw, you throw a left punch.
所以，这是用左手打的一拳，但动词是“throw”，你打出一记左拳。
So, basically, you punch somebody with your left.
所以，基本上，你用左手打某人。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's just another way of saying to punch someone.
所以，这只是说打某人的另一种方式。
To punch someone.
打某人。
Right.
对。
So, Bob started to throw some punches at the other guy.
所以，鲍勃开始向另一个人挥拳。
All right.
好的。
Look over there.
看那边。
That guy's throwing punches.
那家伙在挥拳。
All right.
好的。
So, to throw a left.
所以，打出一记左拳。
To throw a punch.
打出一拳。
Now, again, you can use this in a lot of different ways with a lot of different types of punches.
现在，同样，你可以用很多不同的方式使用这个，搭配很多不同类型的拳法。
So, you could say to throw a jab.
所以，你可以说打出一记刺拳。
Okay.
好的。
Or throw an uppercut.
或者打出一记上勾拳。
Or throw a hook.
或者打出一记勾拳。
Okay.
好的。
So, now that we've seen all these phrases, why don't we listen to the dialogue for the
那么，既然我们已经看到了所有这些短语，我们不妨最后再听一遍对话，
very last time and we'll come back in a little bit.
然后我们一会儿再回来。
Welcome back, boxing fans.
欢迎回来，拳击迷们。
My name is Rick Fields, and here with me is the man with the iron jaw, Bob Copeland.
我是里克·菲尔兹，和我一起的是铁下巴先生，鲍勃·科普兰。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢你，里克。
We're coming to you live from Las Vegas.
我们正在拉斯维加斯为您现场直播。
We're in the beautiful MGM Grand Hotel and Casino, where the World Heavyweight Championship
我们在美丽的米高梅大酒店和赌场，世界重量级冠军赛
is about to get underway.
即将开始。
That's right, Bob.
没错，鲍勃。
We're about to witness the legendary Italian Stallion himself, Rocky Balboa, square off
我们即将见证传奇的意大利种马本人，洛奇·巴尔博亚，与
against his lifetime rival, Apollo Creed.
他的终身对手阿波罗·克里德对决。
This will be a gruesome match for sure.
这肯定是一场残酷的比赛。
Both fighters are in the ring, and we are about to begin.
两位拳手都在擂台上，我们即将开始。
In the blue corner, weighing in at 220 pounds, the former heavyweight champion of the world,
在蓝色角落，体重220磅，前世界重量级冠军，
the master of disaster, the one and only Apollo Creed.
灾难大师，独一无二的阿波罗·克里德。
In the red corner, weighing 218 pounds, and with a record of 47 wins and 37 knockouts,
在红色角落，体重218磅，战绩47胜37次击倒，
the undefeated, undisputed heavyweight champion of the world, the Italian Stallion, Rocky
不败的、无可争议的世界重量级冠军，意大利种马，洛奇
Balboa.
巴尔博亚。
There's the bell, and this fight is underway.
铃声响起，比赛开始了。
Apollo quickly attacks Rocky with quick, strong jabs.
阿波罗迅速用快速有力的刺拳攻击洛奇。
Rocky dodges successfully and counterattacks with a strong right hook.
洛奇成功躲闪，并用一记有力的右勾拳反击。
Apollo is cut.
阿波罗被割伤了。
Rocky landed a strong blow to his right eyebrow and cut him.
洛奇对他的右眉打出了一记重拳，把他割伤了。
This is his chance.
这是他的机会。
Rocky quickly throws a left, right, another left.
洛奇迅速打出一记左拳、右拳、又一记左拳。
Apollo is getting pounded.
阿波罗正在被猛击。
Apollo recovers with a powerful haymaker and catches Rocky off guard.
阿波罗用一记强力的大摆拳恢复过来，打了洛奇一个措手不及。
He's down.
他倒下了。
The ref starts the count.
裁判开始读秒。
One, two, three, four, five.
一、二、三、四、五。
So as I mentioned, Marco, I'm not really that much of a fan or that knowledgeable about
所以，正如我提到的，马可，我其实并不是那么喜欢拳击，也不是很了解
boxing.
拳击。
And actually, this is becoming a theme in these sports lessons, isn't it?
实际上，这在这些体育课中成了一个主题，不是吗？
Well, boxing is a very popular sport in North America.
嗯，拳击在北美是一项非常受欢迎的运动。
I'm not really that big of a fan, but I have seen a couple of matches.
我并不是那么狂热的粉丝，但我看过几场比赛。
And it's very interesting because as we saw in our dialogue, most big fights take place
这很有趣，因为正如我们在对话中看到的，大多数大型比赛都
in Las Vegas at some big hotel.
在拉斯维加斯的某个大酒店举行。
Right.
对。
But you said it's super popular and everyone wants to watch these matches.
但你说它超级受欢迎，每个人都想看这些比赛。
And obviously, everyone can't go to Las Vegas.
显然，不是每个人都能去拉斯维加斯。
So what's the common way for most people to watch these boxing matches?
那么大多数人看这些拳击比赛的常见方式是什么？
Right.
对。
So in the United States, there's something very popular called pay-per-view.
所以在美国，有一种非常流行的东西叫做按次付费。
And I'm sure in your countries, you have something similar.
我相信在你们国家，也有类似的东西。
Basically, pay-per-view, you can buy the fight so you can have access to it and watch it
基本上，按次付费，你可以购买比赛，这样你就可以观看它
on your TV.
在你的电视上。
But you only pay one time to watch like maybe two hours, right?
但你只付一次钱，看比如两个小时，对吧？
Right.
对。
So let's say you're at your house, it's six o'clock and the fight begins at eight.
所以，假设你在家，现在是六点，比赛八点开始。
So you can call your TV cable company or maybe use on the internet with a credit card and
那么你可以打电话给你的有线电视公司，或者可能在网上用信用卡，
they activate it on your TV so you can watch the fight.
他们会在你的电视上激活它，这样你就可以看比赛了。
And when it's over, well, you finished watching it.
当比赛结束时，嗯，你就看完了。
Now, it's pretty expensive, isn't it?
现在，这相当贵，不是吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Pay-per-view can be very expensive depending on what event it is because sometimes it's
按次付费可能非常昂贵，取决于是什么活动，因为有时是
boxing matches, concerts or special events.
拳击比赛、音乐会或特别活动。
So it can maybe cost, I don't know, 60, 80, maybe $100.
所以它可能花费，我不知道，60、80，也许100美元。
So it's very popular for one house to buy the pay-per-view and then many friends come
所以，一个家庭购买按次付费，然后很多朋友过来，
over and everyone chips in with five or $10 and everyone watches it on one TV.
每个人都凑五到十美元，大家一起在一台电视上看，这很常见。
All right.
好的。
So the pay-per-view boxing party, a common way to watch the sport in America.
所以，按次付费的拳击派对，在美国观看这项运动的常见方式。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, why don't you guys visit our website and tell us about boxing.
现在，你们不妨访问我们的网站，告诉我们关于拳击的事。
Do you guys like it?
你们喜欢它吗？
Do you know anything about it?
你们对它了解吗？
Are you guys maybe even boxers yourselves?
你们自己甚至可能是拳击手吗？
Or former boxers.
或者前拳击手。
All right.
好的。
So we'll see you guys at our website and also if you have any questions or comments, be
那么，我们会在我们的网站上见到你们，如果你们有任何问题或评论，
sure to leave them there as well.
也请务必留在那里。
You can find us at EnglishPod.com and until next time, thanks for listening and goodbye.
你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们，下次再见，感谢收听，再见。